# Saurabh **Dubey**

## Software Test Automation Engineer

Address Pune, Maharashtra 411057

**Phone** +91- 9971370912

**E-mail:** hello saurabhdubey@outlook.com

Objective: Seeking a challenging position in a quality growth-oriented IT environment, where my knowledge, skills and experience can contribute towards the growth of the company, to keep always up with the upgrading technologies and to serve the organization with utmost commitment and dedication.

Professional Summary: Working experience of 5+ years in QA Testing, Working as a Software Test Automation Engineer with MASTERCARD. Excellent understanding of technical processes, knowledge of Software Testing life cycle. 5+ Years of experience in Selenium Web-driver. Experience in working with TestNG and Maven frameworks. Experience in Backend Automation using Rest Assured library. Good understanding on Functional Testing including Unit testing, Integration testing, System testing, Sanity testing, Smoke testing, Regression testing.

#### **Skills**

Selenium WebDriver 3 and 4 | Core Java | Web and API
Automation Testing | Jenkins | Postman | Rally | Splunk | Bit
Bucket | OOPs | Junit | Web based Framework | Cucumber |
BDD Framework | TestNG | Maven build automation tool | Data
Driven | Unit, Integration, System, Acceptance Testing | Smoke
Testing | Regression Testing | Sanity Testing | Xpath | CSS |
JMeter | Mobaxterm

**Technologies** : Web UI Automation Testing, Backend Rest API Automation

**Testing Tool** : Selenium Web driver, Postman

Languages : Java

Framework : TestNG, Cucumber BDD Framework, WTF & Cucumber based

Framework, WTF Cycler Framework, STF Framework

IDE : Eclipse, IntelliJ

Version Control Tools : Git, Bit Bucket

**Build Automation** : Maven

# **Work History**

# 2021-08 - Current Project: Mastercard

#### **Software Test Automation Engineer**

Epam Systems, Pune (India)

- Working at Epam Systems as a Software Test Automation Engineer for a Card & Payment Domain based Project.
- Based on the assigned stories, my job is to first analyze the client's requirements and do the test automation.
- Prepare the test plan, the objective of creating the test plan is to prepare test data matrix for automation while considering all the possible scenarios.
- Prepare automation test scripts including UI and API automation where have to perform different transactions altogether.
- By using Selenium Web-driver create test scripts which covered all the possible automation scenarios.
- Execution of the test scripts on all the different environments including devlite and Staging.
- Create the Jenkins job of all the automated scenarios and track them accordingly.
- Uses Splunk to find the root cause of the failures and update on the open issue pages so that anyone can track them.
- Important Member of the Scrum call where we do the stories grooming and assign them to individuals.
- Uses Rally a track management tool to track the defects and the story progress.
- Make the Confluence Pages with respect to assigned feature what in scope or what not.
- Important member of the calls where we discuss about Releases and Regression failures.
- Expertise working on Web Testing and Cucumber framework based on UI and API automation.

#### 2020/08 -2021/08

#### **Quality Analyst**

**Project: WearYourOpinion** 

Synapses LLC, Indore, Madhya Pradesh

- Worked at Synapses LLC as a Quality Analyst on the Applications which directly deal with confidential data.
- Testing an ecommerce application helps in the prevention of errors and adds value to the product by ensuring conformity to client requirements.
- The objective of testing is to ensure Software reliability, Software quality, System Assurance,
   Optimum performance, and capacity utilization. Setting up an
   E-commerce system is a complex process and subject to many market-specific variables.

- To maintain the integrity of the E Commerce system, testing becomes compulsory.
- Creating Automated Test Scripts for various e-commerce applications by using Selenium Web-driver.
- Execution and Maintenance of test scripts based on the requirements. Reviewing of Functional
- requirements/specifications and create test cases accordingly.
- Create Test Cases Using Element locators and Selenium Web driver methods. Enhance and update
- the existing framework as per the requirements.
- Involved in application walk through for clear functional requirements.
- Used various other tools like Pivotal Tracker and Lambda Test according to the requirements of the test cases.
- Working in automation of API testing using REST API.
- Executing test cases verifying the results according to the client requirements. Create detailed,
- comprehensive, and well-structured test plan and test cases. Used updated extent reports
- dependencies to generate more pictorial reports.

## 2019/03 - 2020/06 Project: UrbanClap

#### **Quality Service Analyst**

UrbanClap Technologies, Gurgaon, Haryana

◆ Projects: UrbanClap Application (Mobile + Web) Platform JIRA,

Web Testing, Selenium Web driver Role

- I used to work as a Quality Service Analyst in web-based application which facilitates user to render services for professionals booking.
- It helps user to book the professional to respective web application with respect to service they want.
- This web application also authenticates the user by facilitating them to register themselves by using login pages.
- Created detailed, comprehensive, and well-structured test plans and test cases. Responsible for GUI
- and Functional Testing, using Black Box Testing Techniques.
- Involved in Reviewing of Functional requirements/specifications and create testcases accordingly.
- Worked on various applications to understand the end-to-end flow of the project.
- Involved in BA walkthrough and active participation in defect triage meetings. Executing test
- cases verifying the results according to the client requirements. Used TestNG annotations in •
   the test scripts.
- Execution of test cases based on functional requirements.
- Develop and apply testing process for new and existing products to meet client needs.
- Involvement in Test Execution, Results Analyzing and Defect Reporting and RTM Preparation.
- Execution of Test cases and Reporting defects and Test Scripts generated Using Selenium.
- Involved in Regression Testing using Selenium.
- Preparing Defect report as per severity and priority Education.

Education	
2011-08 - 2016-04	Bachelor of Technology: Electronics and Communications Engineering Arya Institute of Engineering & Technology - Jaipur
2009-07 - 2010-04	Higher Secondary: Mathematics
	Genius Higher Secondary School - Morena
2007-07 - 2008-04	High School: Mathematics and Science  Tulika Convent Higher Secondary School -Morena
Languages	
	English
	Hindi
Interests	
	Watching Short Films

Watching Documentaries